wmata.com 2019-12-20

# Metro Digital Services Privacy Policy | WMATA

Last updated on June 14, 2019.

To read Metro's Digital Services Terms of Use please visit this page.

### Summary

At Metro we respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personally identifiable information (PII) when you use wmata.com and other Metro-owned or operated online properties (referred to throughout this Privacy Policy as Metro's digital services). PII is information that can be used to identify you individually, such as your name, address, and telephone number. This Policy only applies to Metro's digital services. You should examine the privacy policy of any other websites or services that you access from Metro's digital services.

Metro also has a separate corporate privacy policy that protects the privacy of individuals who are the subjects of records maintained in Metro's systems of records. Please read the explanations for general routine uses within the systems of records notices for additional information. Similarly, if a specific service or product offered through Metro's digital services  includes additional privacy provisions, the more strict or specific provision included with that service or product will apply.

We may periodically change the terms without notice, so please check them from time to time as your continued use of the site signifies your acceptance of the terms and conditions, including changed items. If you have any questions or concerns about our digital services privacy policy, please  [contact customer service](http://wmata.custhelp.com/app/home/).

## Policy Details

The links below will take you to specific sections of Metro's digital services  privacy policy for more details on what information we collect and how we use it.

  * Information We Collect and Store Automatically
  * Geolocation
  * Cookies
  * Advertising Cookies
  * Embedded Content
  * Personal Information Collected
  * Protecting Your Information
  * Children's Privacy
  * Employment Application Information
  * Links to Other Sites

### Information We Collect and Store Automatically

Every time you use Metro's digital services, we may automatically collect certain non-PII via Google Analytics and other methods. This information may include but not be limited to your IP address, referring website information from which you access Metro's digital services, the type of browser and operating system you are using, the date and time of your visit, and which pages you visit on Metro's digital services. This information allows us to see trends in usage, to provide you a better experience and to improve our services.

Top

### Geolocation

To provide location-based information for services like the Trip Planner, Metro's digital services may request that your browser or device provide us with your precise location. Your browser or device will require you to give your consent to our collection of location information. We may also aggregate anonymous location data to better understand how people are using these location-enhanced services and later improve those services.

Top

### Cookies

A cookie is information saved by your browser. When you visit our website, we may place a cookie on your browser so we can recognize your device in the future. If you return to our website later on, our servers can read that cookie to remember you from your last visit and keep track of you over time. We use these files to personalize pages, load pages faster, or allow you to conduct e-commerce more easily and to analyze anonymized data to help us understand how people interact with our site so we can make it better.

Metro may use external vendors to deliver services on our behalf, including setting cookies by a third-party (third-party cookies). We do not control these, **please see their individual privacy policies for more information**.

Top

### Advertising cookies

Advertising cookies (or web beacons) are used to show you content relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement, as well as help measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. They are usually placed by advertising networks, with our permission. A web beacon is a transparent image that has been placed on a webpage and sends a signal when a user has visited that page. They may be used to show you content relevant to you and your interests, limit the number of times you see an advertisement, as well as help measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. A web beacon does not contain any personal information. No PII is transmitted to the third party using the web beacon.

Please be aware that these cookies are not controlled by Metro. We do not control these, **please see their individual privacy policies for more information**.

Top

### Embedded content

We may also embed content from websites such as YouTube or Instagram. As a result, when you visit a page featuring such content, you may be presented with cookies in the embedded content from these third-parties. We do not control these cookies and cannot prevent these sites or domains from collecting information on your use of this content. You should check the relevant third-party website for more information about them and how to opt out. If you are not logged in to their services, they will not know who you are but may still gather anonymous usage information.

Top

### Personal Information Collected

Metro collects PII through its digital services only if you choose to provide it to us when using products and services offered. We use this information only for fulfilling your requests. We do not lease or sell your PII to outside companies. However, Metro does contract with third parties to provide you with some of the services you may request online. In order to fulfill your request, Metro may provide your PII to such contractors.

Information collected is owned by Metro and may be used to communicate with you and improve the quality and personalization of your service. PII is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Metro will not sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from Metro's digital services for commercial marketing purposes.

If you do not supply PII for one of the purposes listed above, we make no attempt to identify you individually. Rather, we may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This information is not linked to any PII that can identify any individual person.

Metro may also use PII to provide you with Metro-related information, for example, email about upcoming events and promotions. You have the right to opt out of any service or information you receive via a single Web or email command. Instructions for doing this are included in all Metro communications.

Top

### Protecting your information

We follow industry standard best practices to protect your personal information and protect your data using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you via Metro's digital services, including adherence to Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards ("PCI-DSS") and the Payment Application Data Security Standards (PA-DSS), collectively known as PCI Standards.

The internet, however, is not generally a secure medium of communication and we cannot guarantee the security of any information you input via Metro's digital services or send to us via the internet.

In addition, we may be required to release PII if it is subpoenaed by a court or grand jury. We may also provide statistics based on the information automatically collected from your visit to federal, state, and city officials.

If you believe there is a data security or privacy issue on our digital properties, please contact Customer Service.

Top

### Children's Privacy

Metro does not knowingly solicit or collect PII of children under the age of 13 through its digital services. If at any time Metro learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted PII, it will take all reasonable measures necessary to remove such PII from its databases and not use such PII for any purpose except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others, or as required by law.

Top

### Employment Application Information

If you fill out an application for employment, the information collected will be used by our human resources personnel only to evaluate your qualifications for the job. The information will also be shared with the manager of the hiring department. This information will not be given to anyone outside Metro.

Top

### Links to Other Sites

Metro's digital services contain links to sites owned and operated by third parties that have their own privacy policies. If you have questions regarding the privacy practices of the third-party website, please review that party's privacy policy. Metro does not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of third-party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

Top
